
//Question ba
var questionBank = [{


        main: 'Listening',
        desc: 'Listen to Connor and Keiko talking. Choose the correct answers.',
        question: 'Keiko has been _____ . ',
        option: ['making a movie', 'working', 'reading thrillers'],
        answer: 'working'
    },
    {
        main: 'Listening',
        desc: 'Listen to Connor and Keiko talking. Choose the correct answers.',
        question: 'Chase Taylor is _____ .',
        option: ['an actor', 'a scientist', 'director'],
        answer: 'an actor'
    },
    {
        main: 'Listening',
        desc: 'Listen to Austin and Teresa talking. Choose the correct answers.',
        question: 'Austin\’s friend wanted Austin to _____ . ',
        option: ['put together a science project for him', 'give him a science project', 'take the project to the teacher'],
        answer: 'give him a science project'
    },

    {
        main: 'Listening',
        desc: 'Listen to Austin and Teresa talking. Choose the correct answers.',
        question: 'Teresa said she would _____ .',
        option: ['think about it', 'give the friend the project', 'refuse to help him'],
        answer: 'refuse to help him'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the conversation.',
        question: 'A: This hiking trail is so beautiful. I really enjoy _________ my dogs here.',
        option: ['walk', ' to walk', 'walking'],
        answer: 'walking'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the conversation.',
        question: 'B: So _________ . Uh-oh. There’s a sign.',
        option: ['am I', 'do I', 'can I'],
        answer: 'do I'

    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the conversation.',
        question: 'A: It _________ be new. What does it mean?',
        option: ['must', 'should', 'will'],
        answer: 'must'

    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the conversation.',
        question: 'B: I think it means you _________ to walk dogs here.',
        option: ['can\’t', 'aren\’t allowed', 'don\’t have l'],
        answer: 'aren\’t allowed'

    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct words to complete the conversation.',
        question: 'A: Oh, no. I guess we _________ gone to the park after all.',
        option: ['would have', 'should have', 'must have'],
        answer: 'should have'

    },

    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct clauses to make logical sentences.',
        question: '1. If I moved to the suburbs, _______',
        option: ['I\’d feel sad.', 'I\’ll take some aspirin.', 'I\’d have to learn how to drive.'],
        answer: 'I\’d have to learn how to drive.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct clauses to make logical sentences.',
        question: '2. If I get a high-paying job, _______',
        option: ['I\’ll save more money.', 'I\’d have to learn how to drive.', 'I won\’t have to go to summer school.'],
        answer: 'I\’ll save more money.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct clauses to make logical sentences.',
        question: '3. If I pass the exam, _______',
        option: ['I\’ll save more money.', 'I\’d have to learn how to drive.', 'I won\’t have to go to summer school.'],
        answer: 'I won\’t have to go to summer school.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct clauses to make logical sentences.',
        question: '4. If I found a million dollars, _______',
        option: ['I\’ll save more money.', 'I\’d go straight to the police.', 'I won\’t have to go to summer school.'],
        answer: 'I\’d go straight to the police.'
    },

    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct clauses to make logical sentences.',
        question: '5. If my boyfriend wanted to break up with me, _______',
        option: ['I\’d feel sad.', 'I\’ll take some aspirin.', 'I\’d go straight to the police.'],
        answer: 'I\’d feel sad.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Choose the correct clauses to make logical sentences.',
        question: '6. If I get a headache, _______',
        option: [
            'I\’d feel sad.',
            'I\’ll take some aspirin.',
            'I\’d go straight to the police.'
        ],
        answer: 'I\’ll take some aspirin.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Read each conversation. Choose the correct response.',
        question: 'A: What have you been doing recently?    B: ______________',
        option: [
            'Great, thanks. And you?',
            'I\’ve been looking for a job.',
            'I’ve eaten ice cream.'
        ],
        answer: 'I\’ve been looking for a job.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Read each conversation. Choose the correct response.',
        question: 'A: I can\’t stand hot weather.   B: ______________',
        option: [
            'Neither am I.',
            'Well, so I am.',
            'Really? I don\’t mind.'
        ],
        answer: 'Really? I don\’t mind.'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Read each conversation. Choose the correct response.',
        question: 'A: What would you do if you broke your friend\’s cell phone?    B: ______________',
        option: [
            'I would have given it away.',
            'I don\’t know. What would you do?',
            'I\’ll probably buy another cell phone.'
        ],
        answer: 'I don\’t know. What would you do?'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Read each conversation. Choose the correct response.',
        question: 'A: What do you think that gesture means?  B: ______________',
        option: [
            'It could mean \“good-bye.\”',
            'Yes, it probably does.',
            'Oh, that\’s what it means!'
        ],
        answer: 'It could mean \“good-bye.\”'
    },
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Read each conversation. Choose the correct response.',
        question: 'A: What kinds of hobbies did you have as a child?  B: ______________',
        option: [
            'I\’ve been reading a lot recently.',
            'I used to play video games.',
            'I might collect comic books.'
        ],
        answer: 'I used to play video games.'
    },
                    
    {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Chhose the correct word or phrase to complete each sentence.',
        question: ' I forgot my wallet. Could I _________ $10? I’ll pay you back tomorrow.',
        option: [
            'lend',
            'borrow',
            'spend'
        ],
        answer: 'borrow'
    },
                        {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Chhose the correct word or phrase to complete each sentence.',
        question: 'We want to know what happened. Please _________ us the truth.',
        option: [
            'offer',
            'tell',
            'make'
        ],
        answer: 'tell'
    },
                        {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Chhose the correct word or phrase to complete each sentence.',
        question: ' If Emily says she’ll do something, she usually does. She’s a very _________ person.',
        option: [
            'strict',
            'reliable',
            'moody'
        ],
        answer: 'reliable'
    },
                        {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Chhose the correct word or phrase to complete each sentence.',
        question: 'I thought I had lost my ATM card when, _________ , I found it in my pocket.',
        option: [
            'luckily',
            'unfortunately',
            'sadly'
        ],
        answer: 'luckily'
    },
                        {
        main: 'Grammar',
        desc: 'Chhose the correct word or phrase to complete each sentence.',
        question: 'Jennifer did an _________ job on her report. That\’s why she got a raise.',
        option: [
            'outstanding',
            'absurd',
            'odd'
        ],
        answer: 'outstanding'
    },
]

var question = document.getElementById('question');
var quizContainer = document.getElementById('quiz-container');
var scorecard = document.getElementById('scorecard');
var main = document.getElementById('main');
var desc = document.getElementById('desc');

var option0 = document.getElementById('option0');
var option1 = document.getElementById('option1');
var option2 = document.getElementById('option2');
var option3 = document.getElementById('option3');
var next = document.querySelector('.next');
var previous = document.querySelector('.previous');
var points = document.getElementById('score');
var span = document.querySelectorAll('span');
var stat = document.querySelector('#stat');
var AudioA = document.getElementById('listeningA');
var i = 0;
var score = 0;

//function to display questions
function displayQuestion() {

    for (var a = 0; a < span.length; a++) {
        span[a].style.background = 'none';
    }

    main.innerHTML = '' + questionBank[i].main;
    desc.innerHTML = '' + questionBank[i].desc;
    question.innerHTML = 'Q.' + (i + 1) + ' ' + questionBank[i].question;
    if (i === 4) {
        AudioA.style.display = "none";

    }
    option0.innerHTML = questionBank[i].option[0];
    option1.innerHTML = questionBank[i].option[1];
    option2.innerHTML = questionBank[i].option[2];
    stat.innerHTML = "Question" + ' ' + (i + 1) + ' ' + 'of' + ' ' + questionBank.length;

}

//function to calculate scores
function calcScore(e) {
    if (e.innerHTML === questionBank[i].answer && score < questionBank.length) {
        score = score + 1;

    }
    setTimeout(nextQuestion, 300);
}
//function to display next question
function nextQuestion() {

    if (i < questionBank.length - 1) {
        i = i + 1;
        displayQuestion();

    } else {
        points.innerHTML = score;
        quizContainer.style.display = 'none';
        scoreboard.style.display = 'block'
    }


}

//function to display previous question
function previousQuestion() {
    if (i <= questionBank.length - 1) {
        i = i - 1;
        if (i <= 4) {
            AudioA.style.display = "block";
        }
        displayQuestion();
    }
}
//click events to previous button
previous.addEventListener('click', previousQuestion);
//click events to next button
next.addEventListener('click', nextQuestion);






displayQuestion();

audio.onclick = function() {
    window.addEventListener("click", function() {

        document.querySelector(".iframe").style.display = "block";
        document.querySelector("#close").style.display = "block";


    });



}
var btn = document.getElementById("close");

btn.onclick = function() {

    window.addEventListener("click", function() {

        document.querySelector(".iframe").style.display = "none";

        document.querySelector("#close").style.display = "none";

    });
}

function send_handle() {

    let num = document.getElementById("number").value;
    let msg = document.getElementById("msg").value;
    let msg1 = document.getElementById("msg1");
    msg = points.innerHTML;
    let name = document.getElementById("name").value;
    if (name == "") {
        msg1.innerHTML = "لا يمكنك ترك الاسم فارغا";
        parent.location = "index1A.html?#scorecard";
    } else {
        var win = open(`https://wa.me/${num}?text=أنا الطالب : ${name}%20كود الإختبار هو :9582${msg}_IAOTS`, 'self');
        // win.focus();
    }
}

window.onbeforeunload = function() {
    return "Dude, are you sure you want to leave? Think of the kittens!";
}

var sec = 3600,
    countDiv = document.getElementById("timer"),
    secpass,
    countDown = setInterval(function() {
        'use strict';

        secpass();
    }, 1000);

function secpass() {
    'use strict';

    var min = Math.floor(sec / 60),
        remSec = sec % 60;

    if (remSec < 10) {

        remSec = '0' + remSec;

    }
    if (min < 10) {

        min = '0' + min;

    }
    countDiv.innerHTML = min + ":" + remSec;

    if (sec > 0) {

        sec = sec - 1;

    } else {

        clearInterval(countDown);

        countDiv.innerHTML = 'countdown done';

    }
}
